Animation Number 1
（貝木(かいき)）ん？
Stay out of it
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Ordinarily I prefer my showers hot, but this time only cold water would do.
Animation Number 26
As I felt my body turning blue, I pondered.
Animation Number 27
Just how many people know that I am staying in this hotel?
（貝木）
俺が このホテルに
宿泊していることを
知っている人間は
果たして どれくらいいるだろう
だが
俺の所在を突き止めたとしても
However, even if they pinpointed my location, to put a letter inside a locked hotel room...
鍵の掛かったホテルの部屋の中に
手紙を置くなんて
That's impossible for anyone to do.
そんなことは誰にも不可能だ
There's no way. Is one of the hotel workers colluding with my enemy?
まさか ホテルの従業員に
敵の内通者がいるのか
Enemy?
敵？
What is the enemy?
敵とは何だ？
Isn't my enemy right now that young deity?
俺が今 敵にしているのは
あの幼い神様じゃなかったのか？
Maybe I'm up against some extraordinary syndicate.
俺は ひょっとすると
とんでもない組織を
相手にしているのかもしれない
Figuring I had
Animation Number 307
cooled down quite considerably,
I turned on the hot water,
Animation Number 307
and warmed
my body.
Animation Number 308
Hitagi End          Part Four
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Senjougahara Hitagi
Hey, Kaiki, are you feeling lonely?
（戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)）
ねえ 貝木
あなた寂しいの？
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
You've been calling me each and every night...
こう 毎晩毎晩
電話を
かけてこられてもさ
Senjougahara, I want to ask you something.
（貝木）
戦場ヶ原 聞きたいことがある
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
What? I'm wearing blue lingerie today.
（戦場ヶ原）
何よ？　私の今日の
下着の色はブルーよ
Wake up, Senjougahara.
（貝木）起きろ 戦場ヶ原
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
I'm awake. Mumble, mumble...
（戦場ヶ原）
起きてるわよ
ムニャムニャ
Don't mumble at me.
（貝木）ムニャムニャとか言うな
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Zzz...
（戦場ヶ原）
ＺＺＺＺ(ズズズズ)…
That's not half-asleep, that's fully asleep.
（貝木）
それ 寝ぼけてるじゃなくて
もう寝てるだろ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
What? You calling me out somewhere again?
（戦場ヶ原）
何よ？　また呼び出し？
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Fine, I'll go anywhere for you. Should we meet up at the Mister Donut we went to yesterday?
いいわよ どこにでも
行ってあげるわよ
昨日と同じミスドで
待ち合わせでいい？
No, you don't have to come over today.
（貝木）いや 今日は来なくていい
That's not it. I want to ask you something.
そうではなく聞きたいことがある
What? Is this something serious?
（戦場ヶ原）
何よ？　真面目な話？
Do we ever have something not-so-serious to talk about?
（貝木）
俺と お前との間に
真面目でない話があるのか？
Good point...
（戦場ヶ原）
そりゃ そうだ
I'll just wash up; hold on.
Animation Number 60
I have a new problem now. So I wanted to ask you something.
別の問題が起きた
だから聞きたいことがあるんだ
Ask me anything.
（戦場ヶ原）
何でも聞いてよ
You... Or rather, you and Araragi...
お前… というか
お前と阿良々木(あららぎ)かな
Also, Oshino Shinobu and that girl named Hanekawa.
あとは忍野(おしの) 忍(しのぶ)と
羽川(はねかわ)ってヤツもか
When all you guys tried to solve the issue concerning Sengoku Nadeko...
要は その辺の連中が
千石撫子(せんごくなでこ)の問題を
解決しようとしているときに
つまり
In other words, before you came to me with your request, had anyone gotten in your way?
（貝木）
俺に だましの仕事を依頼する前に
誰かに邪魔されたことはあるか？
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Rather than if someone got in your way, I'm wondering if someone gave you a warning.
（貝木）邪魔… というか
警告されたりしたことはあるか
という意味の
質問だと思ってくれていい
Something like receiving a letter telling you to "pull out"...
例えば“手を引け”と
書かれた手紙が届いたとか
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Something happened?
（戦場ヶ原）
何かあったの？
While I reported on my job's progress,
（貝木）
俺は仕事の報告を兼ねて
I told Senjougahara about the events that happened today.
今日あった出来事を
戦場ヶ原に教えるのだった
I didn't talk about everything that happened.
とはいえ
もちろん その全てではない
But I had no choice but to disclose the info about Ononoki and Gaen-senpai at this point.
ただ 斧乃木(おののき)のこと
それに臥煙(がえん)先輩のことは
ここでは言わざるをえなかった
I see... Gaen-san, huh?
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
（戦場ヶ原）
ふ〜ん 臥煙さんね
She said she was over at your town a while back. Did you get to meet her?
（貝木）
しばらく前に
その町に来ていたらしいが
お前 会っているか？
No, I didn't meet her.
（戦場ヶ原）
いえ 私は会っていない
But Araragi-kun and Hanekawa-san both had something to do with her.
けれど 阿良々木くんと羽川さんが
それぞれ関わっているわ
Or rather, the reason Sengoku Nadeko became a god was because of Gaen-san's talisman to begin with...
というか
千石撫子が神様になったのが
そもそも臥煙さんの
お札のせいで… なんだけれど
Oh, so you knew about that too?
（貝木）
ああ
なんだ お前も知っていたのか
Then, is Gaen-senpai warning Araragi and that Hanekawa like she's warning me?
臥煙先輩は じゃあ
阿良々木や羽川？　とかに
言ってるわけか？
To pull out of this case?
俺に対して言ったように
〝手を引け〞と
She wouldn't say it to Araragi-kun...
（戦場ヶ原）
阿良々木くんには言わないでしょう
Because that's basically telling him to be killed without resisting.
それって 君は抵抗せずに
殺されろってことじゃない
Even a kindergartner would know that's something pretty reckless.
それが むちゃな要求なのは
幼稚園児にだって分かるでしょ
That's true.
（貝木）そりゃ そうだ
But Hanekawa-san has met her once, and I think she said something very unpleasant then.
（戦場ヶ原）
ただ 羽川さんは １度会って
そのときに何か嫌なことを
言われたみたいだったから
So perhaps Araragi was told something of that nature as well.
多分 阿良々木くんも
そういうことを
言われたんじゃないかしら
Hmm...
（貝木）ふん
Though, that said, it doesn't seem like Hanekawa-san was forced to do anything either.
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
（戦場ヶ原）
まあ とはいえ
羽川さんも何かを
強要はされなかった
らしいけれど
In her words, it was more like a piece of advice.
本人いわく
忠告みたいな
感じだったというか
Figures. She didn't force me to do anything either.
だろうな
俺にも強要はしなかった
Though now we've cut connections.
Animation Number 87
Kaiki. If you want to talk to Hanekawa-san right now, I think you should give up on that.
（戦場ヶ原）
貝木 もしも羽川さんに
話を聞いてみたいというのならば
それは諦めたほうがいいわよ
Because Hanekawa-san is overseas right now.
だって 羽川さん 今 海外だもの
Overseas? She looking for Oshino or something?
（貝木）海外？　忍野を捜しにか？
Well then, that's fine.
まあ じゃあいい
In any case, it seems Gaen-senpai fears that I'm going to fail.
ともかく臥煙先輩は
俺が失敗することを
恐れているらしい
That's impossible, but in the case that I don't fulfill your request to deceive Sengoku Nadeko...
ありえないことだが
俺が お前の依頼を完遂できず
千石撫子を
だませなかったパターンを…
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
In that case, as originally planned, Araragi and I just die, right?
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（戦場ヶ原）
その場合は
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
元どおり 私と阿良々木くんが
殺されるだけじゃないの？
That seems like how Gaen-san planned for things to be.
別に臥煙さん的には
予定どおりじゃない
No, I think she fears that Nadeko will go into a frenzy if she realizes she's been deceived.
いや つまり
だまそうという策略そのものに
千石撫子が逆上することを
恐れているという意味だと思う
Well, I kind of understand that.
（戦場ヶ原）
まあ それは なんとなく分かるわね
In other words, it's like if a girl is okay with being rejected,
つまり告白して
ただ振られるのはいいけれど
告白したのに
but can't tolerate it if the guy rejects her by lying that he "already has a girlfriend."
“彼女がいるから”と
ウソをつかれて振られるのは
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
我慢できない
みたいなことなのかしらね
With that,
Animation Number 101
we moved to a metaphorical discussion. Likening it to love obscured it for me entirely.
However,
Animation Number 101
Yeah, that's it. Just like that.
（貝木）
ああ そうだな　そのとおりだ
Then, what you said earlier... You were offered 3 million yen from Gaen-san, right?
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
（戦場ヶ原）
それで
さっきの話じゃ 貝木
あなた 臥煙さんから
300万円という大金を
提示されたのよね？
Why did you refuse? In other words, why didn't you pull out right then?
どうして断ったの？
つまり どうして
そこで手を引かなかったの？
What, you wanted me to pull out?
（貝木）
なんだ 手を引いてほしかったのか
That's not what I mean. But not knowing your intentions makes me uneasy.
（戦場ヶ原）
そういうわけじゃないけれど
あなたの意図が分からないのは
不安になるわ
I understand her feelings, though she says disturbing things like they are nothing.
Animation Number 106
Or did you dodge the situation...
それとも
なんだかんだと
うまく立ち回って
...and figure out some way to end up with more than 3 million yen?
300万円以上のお金を
どこかから
せしめる算段でも
立ったのかしら
I kept quiet.
Animation Number 108
I'm sorry. I said something horrible.
ごめんなさい
ひどいことを言いました
That was easy.
Animation Number 109
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
But really, why?
（戦場ヶ原）
でも
本当に なんでなの？
Of course, I'm grateful that you accepted my offer...
もちろん
仕事を続けてくれることには
感謝をするけれど
...but you can understand my uneasiness, right?
ここで私が不安になるのは
分かるでしょう？
There is no need for me to figure out a means to gain more than 3 million yen.
300万円以上の金を
せしめる算段など
立てる必要はないだろう
俺は既に
その金を手に入れたんだから
Because I already have that money.
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
One hundred thousand yen plus three million yen.
That's three million one hundred thousand yen,
clearly more than three million.
Animation Number 114
Well, that's true...
（戦場ヶ原）
まあ それはそうね
I get the same amount of money whether I continue or I stop...
（貝木）
仕事を続けようと やめようと
同じ額がもらえるのだから
...so of course I'll keep going.
そりゃ 続けるさ
It's very simple logic.
簡単な理屈だ
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
If you were paid the same regardless, wouldn't you quit your job?
（戦場ヶ原）
同じ額がもらえるのなら
仕事を やめない？
That's childish logic. Adults don't toss out their jobs so nonchalantly.
（貝木）それは子供の理屈だな
大人は そう簡単には
仕事を投げ出さない
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Don't treat me like a child.
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
（戦場ヶ原）
子供扱いしないで
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Animation Number 120
That said, Gaen-senpai doesn't matter anymore.
とはいえ 臥煙先輩のことは
もういいんだよ
With my pursuer in mind,
Animation Number 121
It's over and done with.
済んだことだ
She's not the type that would use force to get her way, even if I didn't pull out...
あの人は 俺が300万円を
受け取っておきながら
手を引かないからといって
...after taking the 3 million yen.
実力行使に出るような
タイプじゃない
She's also not the type that would give two warnings.
同じ忠告を２度する人でもない
That's why I'm perplexed.
だから不思議なんだよ
Who is this Cat's Eye that snuck into...
ホテルの俺の部屋に 留守中 侵入し
...my hotel room while I was out, and left a letter with the same message?
同じメッセージを書いた手紙を
置いていったキャッツ･アイは
一体 誰なんだろう
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Well, I don't know who...
（戦場ヶ原）
まあ
誰かは分からないけれど
...but anyone could probably leave a letter in your absence.
でも
あなたが留守中の部屋に
手紙を残すくらい
It wouldn't have to be someone from Cat's Eye.
キャッツ･アイ
でなくとも
それくらいは
できそうなものだけれど
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
You can just slide an envelope underneath the door.
（戦場ヶ原）
封筒なんて
ドアの下から滑らして
入れればいいじゃない
Animation Number 141
I fell silent,
and after contemplating the plausibility of her words,
Animation Number 141
realized there was no refuting her hypothesis.
I see. That's rational to consider.
（貝木）
なるほど 検討に値する推理だな
It's not that difficult for someone to deduce the hotel you're staying in, right?
（戦場ヶ原）
あなたの泊まっているホテルを
特定すること自体は
誰にとっても
そこまで難しくはないでしょう？
At least, it wouldn't be impossible for people that want to stop you from finishing your current job.
少なくとも
あなたが今やっている仕事を
止めたいと思うような人なら
できなくはないはずよ
That guy shadowing you bothers me too...
その尾行者っていうのも
気になるし
Though the shadower may be a completely different case that has nothing to do with this.
（貝木）
尾行者は この件とは
まるで無関係な
別件のヤツかも
しれないがな
True. You've done quite a bit in this town already.
（戦場ヶ原）
そうね
特に あなた
この町で いろいろあったものね
If the two things are unrelated, wouldn't that be more of an issue?
無関係だとすれば
むしろ そのほうが
気になるんじゃないかしら
It's always like this. Nothing to worry about.
（貝木）
いつものことだ
気にならん
I'm more thankful for "the usual" at this point.
むしろ いつものことのほうが
俺にとっては ありがたいな
I don't want work that I expected to wrap up so neatly to suddenly become complicated.
せっかく
簡単に まとまりそうな仕事が
ここにきて
ややこしくなるのは困る
That's why I called you.
で お前に電話したわけだ
I thought that you might have a clue.
ひょっとして 心当たりが
あるんじゃないかと思ってな
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Unfortunately, I don't.
（戦場ヶ原）
残念ながら ないわね
In the first place, I haven't told anyone that I've requested this from you.
そもそも
あなたに依頼したこと自体
私は誰にも言っていないし
Sometimes people find out without you telling them.
（貝木）
言わなくても
バレることはあるだろう
Like, maybe someone overheard you talking to me in the hallway of the Araragi residence?
例えば 阿良々木家の廊下で
俺と話しているのを
誰かに聞かれたとか
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
No.
（戦場ヶ原）
ない
Well, if there's any possibility...
まあ 可能性があるとすれば
...Araragi might have caught on if he checked my cell phone without me knowing?
私に隠れて 阿良々木くんが
私の携帯チェックをしていれば
分かるのかしら？
A boyfriend
Animation Number 151
checking the phone calls
of his girlfriend
Animation Number 151
Come now. Araragi isn't the type that would do such a thing.
おいおい 阿良々木は
そんなまねをするヤツでは
ないだろう
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Yes, right. You're correct.
（戦場ヶ原）
ええ そうね　そのとおりだわ
Besides, even if he caught on to something from my attitude...
それに もしも私の態度から
何かを察したとしても
...he wouldn't be so roundabout in sending out an anonymous note.
匿名の手紙を出すなんて
まどろっこしい まねは
しないでしょう
He'd tell you directly.
直談判に出るはずよ
Right.
（貝木）そうだな
In any case, I guess I'll check it out just in case...
まあ なんにしても
念のために調べておくか
その手紙の差出人は
臥煙先輩と違って
The sender of the letter, unlike Gaen-senpai, may try to hinder me from deceiving Sengoku Nadeko.
千石撫子を だますうえで
俺の邪魔をしてくるかも
しれないしな
True... That letter was hand-written, right?
（戦場ヶ原）
そうね 手書きなのよね？
その手紙
Stay out of it
Yeah, that's right. It was written in a way to try to purposefully hide any characteristics.
（貝木）ああ そうだ
筆跡は意図的に
特徴を消している感じだった
I see. But if I looked at it, I might know who wrote it.
（戦場ヶ原）
そう でも私が見たら
誰か分かるかもしれないわよね
Tonight is too late for sure, but can you show it to me tomorrow or something?
さすがに
今夜は もう無理だけれど
明日にでも
見せてもらえるかしら？
Didn't you say you didn't have a clue?
（貝木）
心当たりは
ないんじゃなかったのか？
Just in case.
（戦場ヶ原）
念のためよ
It's not bad to be so cautious, but that's impossible.
（貝木）
その用心深さは悪くないが
不可能だな
I already ripped up the note and threw it away.
その手紙は 既に破いて捨てた
Huh?
（貝木）
トイレに流したから
つなぎ合わせることも不可能だ
I also flushed it down the toilet, so it's impossible to reassemble.
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Black Scene
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Why did you do such a thing? It's an important piece of evidence.
（戦場ヶ原）
なんで
そんなことをするの？
大事な証拠なのに
Evidence? I'm not a cop.
証拠？　俺は警察じゃないぞ
それに
お前はよく知っているだろう
And you know well enough already.
I always quickly throw out things I don't need...
俺は いらないものや
不愉快なものは手元に残さずに
...or things I find unpleasant and never keep them at hand.
さっさと
捨てることにしているんだよ
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Yes, I know that. That's how you tossed me out too.
（戦場ヶ原）
ええ 確かに知ってるわ
そうやって 私のことも
捨てたんだもんね
What, did I toss you out?
なんだ
お前 俺に捨てられたのか？
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Slip of the tongue.
（戦場ヶ原）
失言 チッ
Pink Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Tch.
Pink Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
I foolishly thought I was talking to Araragi.
うっかり阿良々木くんと
話しているのと
間違えたわ
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
I was unable to determine if she was trying to help me or not.
Oh well, I thought, and ignored that. No point bullying the children.
Animation Number 176
Well, it's a letter that was in my room, which means it was meant for me.
まあ 俺の部屋に
つまり俺宛に出されていた手紙だ
I'll do something about it as part of the job, so you don't have to worry about it.
仕事の一環として
俺がなんとかするから
お前は気にしなくていいし
お前は何もしなくていい
You don't have to do anything.
Just go make out with Araragi.
阿良々木と いちゃついていろ
I can't do that.
（戦場ヶ原）
そうはいかないわ
No, I do want you to do your job, and I'll leave everything concerning the job to you.
いえ もちろん
あなたは あなたの
仕事をしてほしいし
その辺は完全に お任せするけれど
But I have to do what I can as well.
私は私で
できるかぎりのことをしなくっちゃ
That's not much of an effort...
（貝木）
それは心掛けというよりも
俺が手を引いたり
...but she's considering the possibility that I'll "pull out" or even betray and bail on her.
あるいは
裏切って逃げたりした場合を
想定してということだろう
How sensible. Well, I won't ask what she'll be doing.
賢明だ
ま… 何をしているかは聞くまい
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
By the way, Kaiki...
（戦場ヶ原）
ところで 貝木
What?
何だ
Are you really planning on doing the hundred times worship with Sengoku Nadeko? No lies?
（戦場ヶ原）
あなたは本当にウソ偽りなく
千石撫子に
お百度参りをするつもりなの？
Yeah... Oh no, there are lies.
あ… いや ウソ偽りはある
Of course I don't intend to climb those stairs a hundred times.
もちろん 100回も
あの階段を上るつもりはない
Though, I think I'm going to visit every day until the end of January.
ただ １月の末までは
毎日通おうと思っている
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Every day...
（戦場ヶ原）
毎日…
So my expenses are going to be roughly 300,000 yen.
（貝木）
だから出費は
およそ30万円といったところだな
They are necessary expenses, but Gaen-senpai's severance payment is more than enough to cover it.
必要経費ではあるが
臥煙先輩からの手切れ金で
十分に足りる
10,000 yen each time you see her... It sounds like you're frequenting a cabaret club.
（戦場ヶ原）
１回会うたびに１万円とか
なんだかキャバクラ通いみたいね
To be honest, that's a point I'm still uncertain about.
正直に言うと
その点がやっぱり不安だわ
I'm worried that Sengoku Nadeko will beguile you if you see her every day.
あなたが毎日会っているうちに
千石撫子に
篭絡されるんじゃないかって
Senjougahara, what? Are you jealous?
戦場ヶ原
なんだ お前 やいているのか？
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 187
My bad.
悪かった
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
I'm not joking.
（戦場ヶ原）
冗談じゃないのよ
That girl is an enchantress.
魔性なんだから あの子
Did you know Sengoku Nadeko before all this?
（貝木）
お前 千石撫子とは
以前から知り合いだったのか？
No. She was just an acquaintance, a friend, of Araragi-kun...
（戦場ヶ原）
いえ
彼女は阿良々木くんの知り合い
友達というだけで
I didn't even know of her existence until she became a god.
私は彼女が神様になるまで
存在を知りさえしなかったわ
（貝木）
なのに
どうして魔性だと断言できる
Then how can you be sure that she's an enchantress?
The only thing I felt was that she was an airhead.
俺は ただのバカだと感じたぞ
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Really?
（戦場ヶ原）
そうね
But, I can say this precisely because I've never met her...
だけど 私は逆に
会ってないからこそ言えるのよ
I have to advise you... Rethink going to see her every day.
毎日会いに行くというのは
考えたほうがいいと
私としては忠告せざるをえないわ
All right. I'll listen to your advice gratefully.
（貝木）分かったよ
お前からの ありがたい忠告
聞いておこう
Maybe so. It might be better if I didn't go see her every day.
そうだな
毎日は会いに行かないほうが
いいかもしれないな
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
I just hope the snake poison isn't addicting.
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
（戦場ヶ原）
蛇の毒に
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
中毒性がなければ
いいのだけれど
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Senjougahara Hitagi
Sen  jou  gahara
Ungrouped
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Go to the Shrine of the Polar Snake 100 Times
(Until end of January)
Find author of letter
(Importance level 4)
Looking out for people trailing me
(Vigilance level 2)
Don't get seen by Araragi
(Critical)
Find out Gaen's motivation
(Priority level low)
Don't get seen by Araragi's sisters (As possible)
Purchase more strings
for Cat's Cradle
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Playing cat's cradle with Ouroboros once is more than enough in a lifetime.
（貝木）
ウロボロスでの あや取りなんて
人生で１回経験すれば たくさんだ
Animation Number 207
4th of January
After buying string for cat's cradle, I thought of buying something else while I was shopping.
あや取りの ひもを買ったあと
俺は ついでに
何か買い物をしていくことにした
If I put 10,000 yen into the offertory box...
さい銭箱に１万円札を入れれば
あの蛇神(へびがみ)様は
...that snake god will come out happily, saying "Here's Nadeko!"
“撫子だよ〜”と
楽し気に登場するのだろうが
But it felt like I was worried about...
しかし 戦場ヶ原から それを
...how Senjougahara said that it was as if I was "frequenting a cabaret club."
“キャバクラに通っているみたい”
と言われたのを
もしかすると 俺は
気にしているのかもしれなかった
After much thought, I decided to buy some sake and take it up.
No Facsimiles
考えた末
俺は日本酒を買っていくことにした
My conclusion was that men usually don't buy locally brewed sake for the cabaret club girls that they long for.
キャバクラで働く憧れの女性に
なかなか地酒を買って
持っていく男も
いないだろうという判断だ
The ethical criticism about making a junior high girl drink doesn't apply.
女子中学生に
日本酒を飲ませるつもりかという
倫理的な非難は
この場合 当たらない
あいつはもう
女子中学生でもなければ
She's no longer a junior high girl, let alone even human. She is a god.
人間でもない
神様である
They say no god ever refuses sacred sake...
お神酒あがらぬ神はなしという
So much so that if she were not to drink this sake, then she would fail as a god...
むしろ この日本酒を
飲まないくらいだったら
あいつは
神様失格ということになり
...and in a way, the problem would resolve itself.
ある意味
問題は解決するとさえ言える
Wash your heart and body before visiting the gods
How to
wash
your
hands
How to
wash
your
hands
1. put a ladle
of water on
your left hand
2. next on your
right hand
3. hold a little water in your
left hand, and rinse your
mouth. Cover your mouth
with your
hand when
you spit it
out
4. wash your left
hand again,
since it touched
your mouth
5. finally
wash the
ladle's
handle
with the
water left
This way the next person can do the same easily.
Care for each other!
Ten thousand yen were interesting enough, but I wondered what she'd do when you throw twenty thousand in.
Animation Number 222
I was quite curious.
H-Here's, Nade... Huh!
（千石）な… なでで え〜？
I thought she might have died.
Animation Number 224
T-Twenty thousand yen?
に… ２万円？
W-What, Kaiki-san, did you make a mistake?
な… なに？　貝木さん
間違えたの？
返さないよ？
You realize you're not getting this back?
Are you like those arcades recently?
Animation Number 228
Doesn't matter.
（貝木）かまわん
Oh! Are you paying in advance for tomorrow?
（千石）
あ！　明日の分の先払いとか？
That's for today. And...
（貝木）今日の分だ
あと 差し入れだ
...a care package.
あ！　お酒だ
It's sake! I've been wanting to have some!
これ飲んでみたかったの
Looks like she can handle her liquor. Unfortunately, it seems she is a god.
（貝木）
いける口らしい
残念ながら神様のようだ
Dad only drank beer. This is the first time I'm going to have sake!
お父さん
ビールしか飲まなかったからね
日本酒はね 初めて飲むんだよね〜
Kaiki-san, what's the difference between sake and beer?
貝木さん 日本酒とビールって
何が違うのかな？
Sake is made from rice, and beer is made from barley.
（貝木）
米から できているのが日本酒
大麦から できているのが
ビールだよ
Here, I brought you some.
（貝木）ほら 持ってきたぞ
Thanks!
（千石）ありがとう！
Now I can pass the time until I kill Koyomi-oniichan off!
これで
暦おにいちゃんを ぶっ殺すまでの
暇つぶしができるよ
You say passing the time, Sengoku, but cat's cradle is a profound art.
（貝木）暇つぶしと言うがな 千石
あや取りも
なかなか奥が深いんだぞ
Animation Number 249
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Black Scene
Hello, Kaiki Deishu-san.
（羽川）こんにちは 貝木泥舟(でいしゅう)さん
It's a pleasure to meet you. I'm Hanekawa Tsubasa, classmates with Senjougahara and Araragi.
お初にお目にかかります
私 戦場ヶ原と阿良々木の同級生の
羽川 翼(つばさ)と申します
I could still run away, but chose not to.
Animation Number 257
I'm...
（貝木）俺は
...Kaiki Deishu...
貝木泥舟という
Though, there doesn't seem to be much need for self-introductions of that sort.
といった自己紹介は
どうやら あまり必要なさそうだな
I imagine you've heard of me from Senjougahara and Araragi?
さしずめ 戦場ヶ原や阿良々木から
俺のことは聞いている…
とかかな？
Yes.
はい
Though, to be honest...
ただ 正直に申し上げますと
...I knew about you before I heard about you from the two of them.
あの２人から話を聞く前から
私は あなたのことは
存じ上げておりました
I had assisted with an investigation by the Fire Sisters...
ファイヤーシスターズの調査に
協力したことがありまして…
Kids... shouldn't speak in such a humble manner.
（貝木）子供が
（羽川）あ…
そこまで かしこまった言葉遣いを
するものじゃないぞ
You want to talk to me, right? I'll listen. Allow me to listen.
俺に話があるんだろう？　聞くよ
聞かせてもらうよ
It's not like I don't have anything I want to talk to you about either.
俺のほうも
お前に話がないでもない
Fare  3420 Yen
Number   564832
Freeway           En Route                                     Wait              Discount           Select             Forward
Fare  3510 Yen
I heard from Senjougahara that you were overseas right now. What's with that?
俺は戦場ヶ原から
お前は今
海外にいると聞いていたんだが
あれは何だ？
Was that a lie Senjougahara told me to prevent me from contacting you?
俺とお前との接触を防ごうという
つまり戦場ヶ原の
ウソってわけだったのか？
Oh, no, that wasn't a lie.
ああ いえ
それはウソじゃないです
Or rather, Senjougahara-san doesn't think that it is a lie.
というか 戦場ヶ原さんは
それをウソだとは思っていません
She and Araragi-kun both believe that I am currently overseas.
あの子や それに阿良々木くんは
今も まだ
私が海外にいると思っています
ほう
I see...
Fare  5220 Yen
Number   564832
Freeway           En Route                                     Wait              Discount           Select             Forward
Fare  5310 Yen
Well, it's an almost useless effort, kind of like a wasted effort to ease their minds...
ああ いえ…
これってもう
ほとんどムダな努力というか
気休め代わりの
徒労みたいなものなんですけれど
But I thought I might break through by pulling this feint trick.
そういうフェイントをかけることで
突破口が開けるんじゃないか… と
Break through?
突破口？
Yes. Well, I kind of already knew that Oshino-san wasn't overseas.
（羽川）そう
まあ
忍野さんが海外にいないことも
私には もう
なんとなく分かってたんですけれど
So I felt that I still did it because I had nothing to lose.
それでも ダメ元という気持ちも
あったんですけれど
Road
narrows
Please
take
another
route
during the
construction
Please
take
another
route
during the
construction
But I thought I'd be able to fool something, be able to go unobserved, if I went overseas once.
一旦 国外に出ることで
何か
ごまかせるんじゃないかなって
目を盗めるんじゃないかって
Go unobserved... From who?
目を盗める… というのは
誰のだ？
From Sengoku Nadeko?
千石撫子のか？
There's that too. But if I were to name someone, it'd probably be Gaen-san.
（羽川）
それも そうなんですけれど
どちらかといえば
臥煙さんでしょうか
Fare  9720 Yen
Number   564832
Freeway           En Route                                     Wait              Discount           Select             Forward
Fare  9810 Yen
True. I heard you directly received some advice from Gaen-senpai.
そうだな
お前は臥煙先輩から
直接 忠告を受けたと聞いている
How to put it... What a misfortune.
何というか災難だったな
I wanted her to think that I was taking irrelevant actions, so to say...
（羽川）
あの人に
私が的外れな行動を取っていると
思ってほしかったと言いますか
So I did come back home for an instant like this, but I'm going to fly out again tomorrow morning.
だから 一瞬こうして
故国に戻ってきましたけれど
また明朝には
飛んでいくつもりです
Coming back for an instant... Is there some meaning in using such precious time to contact me?
一瞬 戻って
そんな貴重な時間に
俺と接触する意味があるのか？
Yes, there is.
ええ あります
It seems like this sort of thing is pretty useless against Gaen-san, who knows everything.
何でも知ってる臥煙さんには
そんな手 あんまり
意味がなさそうなんですけれど
But by going overseas, it was easier for Senjougahara-san to act.
でも 私が海外に出たことで
戦場ヶ原さんが動きやすくなって
And I was glad to find out she got in touch with you.
あなたに連絡を取ったことは
よかったと思います
It was a happy miscalculation, or rather, a happy calculation gone as planned.
うれしい誤算というか
うれしい計算どおりでした
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（羽川）
貝木さん
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Black Scene
Kaiki-san.
Animation Number 'none'
Black Scene
So she said, looking deep into my eyes.
Animation Number 284
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
I'd never met anybody who could
look someone in the eye so earnestly.
Animation Number 285
Please help Senjougahara-san out.
戦場ヶ原さんを
助けてあげてくださいね
Animation Number 287
If you don't mind, I'd like to talk in the hotel room where I'm staying.
（羽川）よければ
私が宿泊しているホテルで
話したいんですけれど
Would that be all right?
かまいませんか？
It's a cheap room, so I'm sure it's a different hotel from where you are staying...
安い部屋ですので
Sidewalk
Do not park your vehicles
きっと貝木さんとは
違うホテルなんでしょうけれど
...but I also have a room in this area.
私も今 このあたりに
宿を取っているんです
I don't mind, but...
（貝木）
俺は かまわないが しかし…
Oh, that's fine.
Happy
New Year's
（羽川）ああ 大丈夫です
I don't mind things like that too much.
私 そういうの
あんまり気になりませんし
それに
Besides...
I think I do have a good eye for men.
男を見る目は あるつもりですから
The hotel where she lodged
Animation Number 306
You know, Hanekawa, you have something to talk to me about...
（貝木）なあ 羽川
お前は俺に話があるし
...and I have something to talk to you about.
俺もお前に話がある
So I'm not reluctant to talk about those things.
だから それについて話をするのは
やぶさかじゃあない
Or rather, I'd like to talk about them.
というか 望むところなのだが
But first, I want to ensure our intentions are identical. Is that okay?
その前に 意思の統一を
図っておいていいかな？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Identical intentions?
意思の統一ですか？
Yeah. It seems that for this current case...
どうも 今回の件じゃあ
...all sorts of people are thinking all sorts of things, and many opinions are crossing over.
いろんなヤツが
いろんなことを考えて
さまざまな思惑が
交錯しているようなのでな
To those that make a living from work of my sort, people's feelings are most important.
俺のような仕事を
なりわいとしている者には
人の気持ちが いちばん大切なんだ
I see.
Half-hearted
Animation Number 333
That's why I want to know.
（貝木）だから知っておきたい
Hanekawa, your position is one to "save" Senjougahara and Araragi, yes?
羽川 お前の立ち位置は
戦場ヶ原や阿良々木を
助けるって方向でいいんだな？
I want to save Senjougahara-san and Araragi-kun.
私は戦場ヶ原さんや阿良々木くんを
助けたいです
But, it doesn't have to be me who saves them.
だけど 助けるのは別に
私じゃなくてもいいんです
I just don't want those two to die, so I don't care who saves them.
（羽川）
私は
あの２人に死んでほしくないだけで
だから
助けるのは誰でもいいんです
Whether it be me, Oshino-san, or you...
私でも
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（羽川）
忍野さんでも
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（羽川）あなたでも
Do you swear to a god?
（貝木）神に誓うか？
I swear to a cat.
猫に誓います
What the hell?
Animation Number 359
That's not an expression that I know of,
but perhaps this is some high schooler code.
Animation Number 359
I can't really deal with slang.
Everything is leaving me behind.
Animation Number 359
You're not going to ask?
（貝木）お前は聞かないのか？
（羽川）え？
You're not going to ask me anything?
（貝木）
お前からは俺に対して
何も聞かないのか？
Where I stand, or rather, how I feel?
俺の立ち位置…
というか 俺の気持ちってやつを
My client, Senjougahara, seems to worry about those a whole lot.
依頼人である戦場ヶ原自身は
えらく気にしているぞ
You don't want to confirm those with me?
お前は
それを俺に確認しないのか？
Do you wonder why I accepted Senjougahara's request?
どうして
俺が戦場ヶ原の依頼を受けたのか
And whether or not I intend on going through with the request?
そして 本当に その依頼を
全うする気があるのかどうかを
I'm not going to ask.
（羽川）聞きません
Well, then, I'd like to delve into the main topic...
え〜っと じゃあ
本題に入らせてほしいんですけれど
Wait.
待て どうして聞かない？
Why aren't you asking? Are you saying that you can see through my feelings?
俺の気持ちなんぞ
お見通しだとでも言うつもりか？
So those sorts of things aren't even worth asking...
そんなことは
聞くまでもないということか
Hmph, it seems like you know everything, young lady.
ふん
どうやら お嬢ちゃん
お前は何でも知っているんだな
It's not that I know everything. I just know what I know.
何でもは知りません
知ってることだけ
Fine...
（貝木）いいだろう
（羽川）はい？
Yes?
Let's get to the main topic. How about we exchange some information, Hanekawa?
本題に入ろう
お互いに情報交換ってやつを
しようじゃないか
羽川
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐(かれん)）
火憐だぜ！
Karen here!
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
（月火(つきひ)）
月火だよ！
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Love!
（２人）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ！
（火憐）
男兄弟だったら
If we were male siblings, we would be the Fire Misters!
Nadeko won't leave until she becomes a goddess!
We're in a bind...
ファイヤー
ミスターズだぜ！
（月火）
いや ファイヤー
ブラザーズでしょ
More like Fire Brothers.
（火憐）
予告編ク〜イズ！
Preview Quiz!
（月火）
ク〜イズ！
Quiz!
Have you heard of mudslinging?
（火憐）
泥仕合って言うじゃんか
I already told you
of a way to become
a goddess, remember?
High Dive
Ah! I remember!
（月火）
言う言う 言っちゃう
言いまくっちゃう！
I've heard of it, heeded it, listened to it!
Team A and Team B are waging an all-out mudslinging war. Who do you think's gonna win?
（火憐）
ＡチームとＢチームが
現在 絶賛 泥試合中です
さて どっちが
勝ったでしょう？
......Sob.
To think they saw the
proper way in my handbook.
Sounds like a real quiz, that's a first—
（月火）
本当にクイズっぽく…
新鮮だな〜
（火憐）
どっちが
勝ったでしょ〜？
WHO's gonna win?
（月火）
泥仕合っていうんだから
If they're both throwing dirt at each other, nobody's going to win.
決着は
つかなかったんじゃ
ないの？
（火憐）
ブブ〜！
正解は引き分け
Wrong, the right answer is: It ends in a draw. Why is that? Because "DRAW-jiai"!
なぜなら
ドロー試合だから
Next time! Koimonogatari Episode 5!
Next Time
Hitagi End Part 5
（２人）
次回「恋物語 第５話
ひたぎエンド 其ノ伍(そのご)」
Hitagi End, Part 5.
You do realize that a draw means nobody wins, right?
I didn't become a goddess but ended up a human sacrifice instead!
（月火）
引き分けなら
決着はつかなかったで
正解では？